In India, we have these huge families.
في الهند، لدينا هذه العائلات الضخمة.
I bet a lot of you all must have heard about it.
أراهن أن الكثير منكم سمع عن ذلك.
Which means that there are a lot of family events.
وهو ما يعني أن هناك الكثير من المناسبات العائلية.
So as a child, my parents used to drag me to these family events.
ولذا عندما كنت طفلاً، اعتاد والداي أخذي لمثل هذه المناسبات،
But the one thing that I always looked forward to
ولكن الشيء الوحيد الذي كنت دائماً أتطلع له
was playing around with my cousins.
هو اللعب مع أبناء عمومتي،
And there was always this one uncle
وكان هناك دائماً عم واحد
who used to be there,
اعتاد أن يكون هناك،
always ready, jumping around with us,
ودائماً جاهز للقفز معنا،
having games for us,
وإيجاد ألعاب لنا،
making us kids have the time of our lives.
وجعلنا نحن الأطفال نمضي أفضل أوقات حياتنا.
This man was extremely successful:
هذا الرجل كان ناجحاً للغاية:
he was confident and powerful.
وكان واثق وقوي،
But then I saw this hale and hearty person deteriorate in health.
ولكن بعدها رأيت هذا الرجل القوي والمعافى تتدهور صحته.
He was diagnosed with Parkinson's.
حيث تم تشخيص حالته بأنه مصاب بالشلل الرعاشي.
Parkinson's is a disease that causes degeneration of the nervous system,
الشلل الرعاشي هو من الأمراض التي تسبب انهيار بالنظام العصبي،
which means that this person who used to be independent
مما يعني أن هذا الشخص الذي اعتاد أن يكون معتمداً على نفسه
suddenly finds tasks like drinking coffee, because of tremors, much more difficult.
يجد فجأة مهام بسيطة مثل شرب القهوة بسبب الهزات أصعب بكثير.
My uncle started using a walker to walk,
بدأ عمي باستخدام مشاية للمشي،
and to take a turn,
وحتى يستطيع الالتفاف،
he literally had to take one step at a time, like this,
فهو بحاجة حرفياً إلى اتخاذ خطوة كاملة مرة واحدة، كهذه،
and it took forever.
واستغرق هذا الأمر طويلاً.
So this person, who used to be the center of attention
لذلك فإن هذا الشخص، الذي اعتاد أن يكون مركز الانتباه
in every family gathering,
في كل اجتماع للعائلة
was suddenly hiding behind people.
بدأ يختبيء فجأة وراء الناس.
He was hiding from the pitiful look in people's eyes.
لقد كان يختبيء من نظرات الشفقة من عيون الناس،
And he's not the only one in the world.
وهو ليس الوحيد في العالم.
Every year, 60,000 people are newly diagnosed with Parkinson's,
ففي كل عام 60،000 شخص يتم تشخيصهم بمرض الشلل الرعاشي،
and this number is only rising.
وهذا الرقم آخذ في الارتفاع،
As designers, we dream that our designs solve these multifaceted problems,
ونحن كمصممين ،نحلم بأن تحل تصميماتنا هذه المشكلة المتعددة الأوجه،
one solution that solves it all,
حل واحد يحل المشكلة بأكملها،
but it need not always be like that.
ولكن لا يلزمها دائماً ان تكون كذلك.
You can also target simple problems
حيث يمكنك أيضاً استهداف مشاكل بسيطة
and create small solutions for them and eventually make a big impact.
وإيجاد حلول بسيطة لها يكون لها تأثير كبير في نهاية المطاف.
So my aim here was to not cure Parkinson's,
هدفي هنا ليس معالجة مرض الشلل الرعاشي،
but to make their everyday tasks much more simple,
ولكن جعل المهام اليومية التي يقوم بها المرضى أكثر سهولة،
and then make an impact.
ومن ثم إحداث تأثير.
Well, the first thing I targeted was tremors, right?
حسناً، الشي الأول الذي قمت باستهدافه هو مشكلة الرعاش، أليس كذلك ؟
My uncle told me that he had stopped drinking coffee or tea in public
لقد اخبرني عمي أنه لم يعد يشرب الشاي أو القهوة في الأماكن العامة،
just out of embarrassment,
تجنباً للحرج ،
so, well, I designed the no-spill cup.
لذا قمت بتصميم كوب لا يتسرب منه السائل.
It works just purely on its form.
فهو يعمل ببساطة حسب شكله.
The curve on top deflects the liquid back inside every time they have tremors,
فالانحناء الموجود بأعلى الكوب يجعل السائل ينحرف للداخل في كل مرة تأتيهم الرعشة،
and this keeps the liquid inside compared to a normal cup.
مما يجعل السائل في الداخل على عكس الكوب العادي.
But the key here is that it is not tagged as a Parkinson's patient product.
ولكن الفكرة هنا هو أنه لم يتم وضع علامة عليه كمنتج خاص بمرضى الرعاش.
It looks like a cup that could be used by you, me, any clumsy person,
بل يبدو كمنتج يمكن استخدامه من قبلك وقبلي ومن قبل أي شخص آخر
and that makes it much more comforting for them to use, to blend in.
وهذا يجعل الأمرأكثرراحة لهم وأسهل اندماجاً.
So, well, one problem solved,
حسناً، مشكلة واحدة تم حلها،
many more to go.
ستتبعها خطوات أخرى عديدة.
All this while, I was interviewing him,
كل هذا حصل بينما كنت أجري مقابلة معه،
questioning him,
وأوجه أسئلة له،
and then I realized that I was getting very superficial information,
وبعدها أدركت انني حصلت على معلومات سطحية جداً،
or just answers to my questions.
أو مجرد أجوبة لأسئلتي،
But I really needed to dig deeper to get a new perspective.
ولكن ما أنا بحاجة إليه هوتعمق أكبر للحصول على منظور جديد.
So I thought, well, let's observe him in his daily tasks,
لذا، فكرت وقلت حسناً، دعونا نلاحظ المهام اليومية التي يقوم بها،
while he's eating, while he's watching TV.
خلال أكله للطعام، وخلال مشاهدته للتلفاز،
And then, when I was actually observing him walking to his dining table,
ومن ثم، عند ملاحظتي له وهو يمشي لطاولة طعامه،
it struck me, this man who finds it so difficult to walk on flat land,
أدهشني ذلك، فكيف لهذا الرجل الذي يجد صعوبة في المشي على أرض مسطحة،
how does he climb a staircase?
أن يصعد سلم الدرج ؟
Because in India we do not have a fancy rail that takes you up a staircase
لأننا لا نملك في الهند هذه الأدراج الفاخرة التي توصلك للأعلى
like in the developed countries.
مثل تلك الموجودة في الدول المتطورة .
One actually has to climb the stairs.
فالشخص بحاجة لأن يصعد الدرج بنفسه،
So he told me,
لذلك قال لي،
"Well, let me show you how I do it."
"حسناً، دعيني أريكي كيف أفعل ذلك."
Let's take a look at what I saw.
دعونا نلقي نظرة حول الشيء الذي رأيته.
So he took really long to reach this position,
علماً انه استغرق وقتا طويلاً حقاً للوصول إلى هذا الموقف،
and then all this while, I'm thinking,
وبعد كل ذلك الوقت، وبينما أفكر،
"Oh my God, is he really going to do it?
"يا إلهي، هل هو حقاً ذاهب للقيام بذلك؟
Is he really, really going to do it without his walker?"
هل حقاً يريد القيام بذلك بدون استخدام المشاية ؟"
And then ...
ومن ثم ...
(Laughter)
(ضحك )
And the turns, he took them so easily.
قام بصعود ونزول الدرج بكل سهولة.
So -- shocked?
هل صدمتم ؟
Well, I was too.
حسناً، لقد صدمت أيضاً.
So this person who could not walk on flat land
ولذلك فإن هذا الشخص الذي لم يستطع المشي على أرض مسطحة
was suddenly a pro at climbing stairs.
فجأةً استطاع صعود السلالم.
On researching this, I realized that it's because it's a continuous motion.
وعند البحث عن هذا، أدركت أن سبب ذلك هو أنها حركة مستمرة.
There's this other man who also suffers from the same symptoms
هناك رجل آخر يعاني أيضاً من نفس الأعراض
and uses a walker,
ويستخدم المشاية،
but the moment he's put on a cycle,
لكن اللحظة التي يوضع بها على الدراجة الهوائية
all his symptoms vanish,
تتلاشى كل أعراضه،
because it is a continuous motion.
بسبب الحركة المستمرة.
So the key for me was to translate this feeling of walking on a staircase
لذلك كان المفتاح بالنسبة لي هو ترجمة هذا الشعور من المشي على الدرج
back to flat land.
على الأرض المسطحة.
And a lot of ideas were tested and tried on him,
والكثير من الأفكار تم اختبارها عليه،
but the one that finally worked was this one. Let's take a look.
ولكن الفكرة التي نجحت أخيراً كانت هذه. لنلقِ نظرة.
(Laughter)
(ضحك )
(Applause)
(تصفيق )
He walked faster, right?
لقد مشى بشكل أسرع، أليس كذلك؟
I call this the staircase illusion,
أنا أسمي هذا بالسلم الوهمي،
and actually when the staircase illusion abruptly ended, he froze,
في الواقع عندما ينتهي هذا الدرج الوهمي، يرتعد من الخوف،
and this is called freezing of gait.
وهذا ما يسمى بتجمد الخطوات.
So it happens a lot,
لذلك يحدث هذا كثيراً،
so why not have a staircase illusion flowing through all their rooms,
إذاً، لماذا لا يكون لدينا سلم وهمي موجود في جميع الغرف،
making them feel much more confident?
مما يجعلهم يشعرون بالثقة أكثر وأكثر؟
You know, technology is not always it.
كما تعلمون، التكنولوجيا ليست دائما الحل.
What we need are human-centered solutions.
ما نحتاجه هو حلول محورها الإنسان.
I could have easily made it into a projection,
كان بإمكاني بسهولة عمل ذلك من خلال عرض الصور
or a Google Glass, or something like that.
أو نظارات جوجل، أو شيء من هذا القبيل.
But I stuck to simple print on the floor.
ولكنني تمسكت بالطباعة البسيطة على الأرض.
This print could be taken into hospitals
يمكن أن تؤخذ هذه المطبوعات الى المستشفيات
to make them feel much more welcome.
لجعلهم يشعرون بترحيب أكثر.
What I wish to do is make every Parkinson's patient
ما أود أن أفعله هو جعل كل مريض رعاش
feel like my uncle felt that day.
يشعر بشعور عمي ذلك اليوم.
He told me that I made him feel like his old self again.
لقد قال لي أنني جعلته يشعر مثل شخصيته القديمة مرة أخرى.
"Smart" in today's world has become synonymous to high tech,
"الذكاء" في عالم اليوم أصبح مرادفاً للتكنولوجيا الفائقة،
and the world is only getting smarter and smarter day by day.
والعالم يزداد ذكاءاً يوماً بعد يوم.
But why can't smart be something that's simple and yet effective?
ولكن لماذا لا يكون الذكاء شيئاً بسيطاً وذا فعالية بنفس الوقت ؟
All we need is a little bit of empathy and some curiosity,
كل ما نحتاج إليه هو القليل من التعاطف وبعض الفضول،
to go out there, observe.
الذهاب الى هناك، والمراقبة.
But let's not stop at that.
ولكن دعونا لا تتوقف عند هذا الحد.
Let's find these complex problems. Don't be scared of them.
دعونا نعثر على هذه المشاكل المعقدة. لا تكونوا خائفين منها.
Break them, boil them down into much smaller problems,
قم بتجزأة هذه المشاكل وإعادة تشكيلها الى مشاكل أصغر،
and then find simple solutions for them.
ومن ثم قم بإيجاد حلول بسيطة بالنسبة لها.
Test these solutions, fail if needed,
اختبر هذه الحلول، إفشل إذا لزم الأمر،
but with newer insights to make it better.
ولكن مع أفكارجديدة لجعلها أفضل.
Imagine what we all could do if we all came up with simple solutions.
تخيل ما يمكننا جميعاً فعله إذا توصلنا جميعاً لهذه الحلول،
What would the world be like if we combined all our simple solutions?
كيف سيكون العالم إذا قمنا بجمع كل حلولنا البسيطة
Let's make a smarter world, but with simplicity.
دعونا نجعل العالم أكثر ذكاءاً، ولكن مع البساطة.
Thank you.
شكراً.
(Applause)
(تصفيق )